# LAYNE J. VASHRO

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Born in USA, 8 December 1983

email layne.vashro@anthro.utah.edu

website http://www.laynevashro.com

phone (M) +1 (801) 663 6199

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Ph.D. in a quantitative subfield of anthropology. In my spare time, I use a personal database of NBA, NCAA, and international basketball data to produce publicly available models and statistical tools. I am interested in continuing my basketball research professionally as a consultant or a fulltime analyst.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D.	The University of Utah, Anthropology
M.S.	The University of Utah, Anthropology
B.S.	Pennsylvania State University, Psychology
B.A.	Pennsylvania State University, Anthropology

#### PUBLISHED WORK

## **Draft Projection Models**

## laynevashro.shinyapps.io/preds/

Collection of draft projection models with predictions for current class and out-of-sample retrodictions to 1990  $\,$ 

#### 5-Factor RAPM Ratings

(Currently private)

Regularized adjusted on/off measure of NBA players' impact on the traditional four-factors on offense and defense, and a 5th factor "pace"

### NCAA and NBA Player Comparison Tools

laynevashro.shinyapps.io/comps/; laynevashro.shinyapps.io/comps\_nba/ Interactive tools that use a simple algorithm to identify statistically closest previous player-seasons to given players' season based on user specified weights

## NCAA and NBA Player Progression Tools

laynevashro.shinyapps.io/progs/; laynevashro.shinyapps.io/progs\_nba/ Interactive tools that track player improvement in each statistic within and between seasons

## Coach Adjustment Tool

#### laynevashro.shinyapps.io/coach\_cors/

Interactive tool that looks at the NCAA-to-NBA correlation of each boxscore statistic for players under each NCAA coach. Helps identify system effects in order to better project future production

#### Coaching Networks

laynevashro.shinyapps.io/coach\_net/

Generates coaching networks around a user-selected NCAA coach

## **Basketball Writing**

I have written a number of articles for different basketball websites. Here is a link to one representative article. More are available on my website or upon request.

#### **Academic Publications**

Full list of my peer-reviewed publications and conference presentations is available upon request.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

2014–Present Postdoctoral Researcher, SCAN Project

Research design, as well as data collection, management, and analysis for the Spatial Cognition and Navigation multidisciplinary research project Reference: Elizabeth Cashdan · ecashdan@gmail.com

2008–2014 Research Assistant, University of Utah, Department of Anthropology

Designed and executed dissertation fieldwork in northwestern Namibia Reference: Steven Josephson • stevencjosephson@gmail.com

2010–2013 Lecturer, University of Utah, Department of Anthropology

Designed and lectured both traditional and online courses at the University of Utah

2010–2012 Project Data Manager, Evans Evaluation

Designed and managed project databases for a research consulting team Reference: Matt Evans · matt@evansevaluation.com

2009–2010 Grant Writer, Institute for Research and

Evaluation

Designed and outlined research grants as a part of a consulting team. Focused on methods and statistical analysis protocol

Reference: Joseph White · joseph.ire@gmail.com

2006–2007 Research Assistant, Pennsylvania State University, Neuroendocrinology Laboratory

Biological sample processing and data entry Reference: Sonia Cavigelli · s-cavigelli@psu.edu

2005–2006 Research Assistant, Pennsylvania State University, Laboratory for Cognition and Action.

Administered experiments to participants and engaged in weekly laboratory discussions about cognitive motor science

Reference: David Rosenbaum · dar12@psu.edu

OTHER INFORMATION

Statistical Skills Generalized Linear Models · Ridge Regression · Mixed Effects Models

· Nonlinear Models · Machine Learning · Logistic Regression · Multinomial Regression · Survival Analysis · Non-Parametric ·

K-MEANS CLUSTERING · PATH ANALYSIS · DATA VISUALIZATION

Computer Skills R · SPSS · Python · html · Ruby

 $MySQL \cdot \ Gnumeric \cdot \ OpenOffice \ Calc \cdot \ Microsoft \ Excel$ 

Beamer · Shiny · Microsoft PowerPoint · GIMP · Inkscape

Awards 2013 · Human Behavior and Evolution Society 2013 New Investigator Finalist

2012–2013 · Wenner-Gren Foundation Dissertation Fieldwork Grant
2012 · Society for Anthropological Sciences 2012 Student Paper Prize

2010–2012 · DDI Grant: National Science Foundation 1026373

Languages English · Mothertongue

Herero · Intermediate

Swahili · Basic

June 18, 2015